<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Day 1 on Know me better..</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/</link><description>Recent content in Day 1 on Know me better..</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Day 1</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day1/</guid><description> Kickstarted a day with a team discussion on Git, and how we can put it to best of its use. Working around with configuration of files to sort out a few kinks, and deploying updated website locally. Learning about CI/CD and basics of GitHub actions and attempt to host the site.</description></item><item><title>Day 10</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day10/</guid><description>Had a team presentation early in the morning.
Tried few Git commands like git stash, git stash apply and git checkout. Randomly experimented around Git. Gitlog till 18 June. Learnt about basics of Cloud Computing, its use in the industry, virtual networks and three basic models of services offered by the cloud services.
IAAS(Infrastructure as a Service) PAAS(Platform as a Service) SAAS(Software as a Service) Started learning and got introduced to Terraform.</description></item><item><title>Day 11</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day11/</guid><description>Installed Terraform on terminal, following the steps in the given doc- Step-by-step guide on Terraform installation Made a Docker container out of Terraform and locally hosted the Nginx image.
Created a new directory. Initialized Terraform in it by using terraform init command. Created main.tf file. Specified resources and providers there. Finally ran the image on LocalHost:8000 ![Nginx Image hosted using Terraform](/posts/Daily Updates/nginxsiteterraformday11.PNG) Learnt some of the basic Terraform commands like plan, apply , destroy along the way.</description></item><item><title>Day 12</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day12/</guid><description>Created my first AWS server-
Launched an Ubuntu instance on AWS console. Selected t2.micro as instance type. Referred thedoc and copied resources tag. Fetched the AMI from Aws management console, for my instance and specified instance type in main.tf file. Successfully deployed 1st ec-2 instance using terraform. resource &amp;quot;aws_instance&amp;quot; &amp;quot;my-first-server&amp;quot; { ami = &amp;quot;ami-0c1a7f89451184c8b&amp;quot; instance_type = &amp;quot;t2.micro&amp;quot; } Through main.tf file, we are indicating terraform what our code should look like in the end.</description></item><item><title>Day 16</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day16/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day16/</guid><description>An attempt to deploy a VM as an IAM user.
Created a directory and initialized Terraform in it. Installed AWS CLI package whic is required for using aws commands.
Used aws configure to provide necessary fields like Access Key ID, Secret Access Key, Default Region and Default Output Format. Though, the since the credentials were revoked, it didn&amp;rsquo;t work out.</description></item><item><title>Day 17</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day17/</guid><description>Continuation of previous day&amp;rsquo;s project on making a webserver-
Passed on some user data in the file.
#Passing on user data to run some commands. user_data = &amp;lt;&amp;lt;-EOF #!/bin/bash sudo apt update -y sudo apt install apache2 -y sudo systemct1 start apache2 sudo bash -c 'echo my first web-server &amp;gt; /var/www/html/index.html' EOF tags = { Name = &amp;quot;web-server&amp;quot; } Found out that there were errors in defining cidr_blocks IP addresses.</description></item><item><title>Day 18</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day18/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day18/</guid><description>Working with VM.
Created a tag for VM.
aws ec2 create-tags --resource i-08431b825258399a3 --tags Key=Name,Value=SkvInstance Stopped the VM once I was done with my experimentation.
aws ec2 stop-instances --instance-ids i-08431b825258399a3 Terminated an instance created previously.
aws ec2 terminate-instances --instance-ids i-09165cb7fe11c4b0b Experimentation with S3 Storage Buckets.
Made a Bucket manually on Console. Later deleted it to repeat the process on AWS.</description></item><item><title>Day 19</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day19/</guid><description>Experimentation with various AWS resources using CLI.
Created a VPC.
aws ec2 create-vpc --cidr-block 10.10.1.0/24 Attempted making a subnet linked to that VPC, but failed since the CIDR turned out to be invalid.
aws ec2 create-subnet --vpc-id vpc-0fd87e36fb326f175 --cidr-block 10.10.1.0/16 Created Internet Gateway and attached it to a VPC.
aws ec2 create-internet-gateway aws ec2 attach-internet-gateway --vpc-id vpc-0fd87e36fb326f175 --internet-gateway-id igw-0f75ad3c966f9bb6b Created a route-table and linked the route to the gateway as well.</description></item><item><title>Day 2</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day2/</guid><description> Discussion on how GitCommits can be put to best of their use. Modified some content on my Hugo website and added a &amp;lsquo;Recent Posts&amp;rsquo; section. Did some further research on GitHub actions and CircleCI. Made a workflow for deployment of my HugoSite, ran a build on GitHub actions, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t get the desired results.</description></item><item><title>Day 20</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day20/</guid><description>Started working around with Kubernetes.
Made a directory kubernetesinstallation for storing private keys.
Created a VM to be used as a Master Node for my Kubernetes installation process.
aws ec2 run-instances --image-id ami-0c1a7f89451184c8b --count 1 --key-name masternodessh --instance-type t2.micro First attempt to connect to my Master Node using SSH.
Attempted connecting to my Master Node VM via SSH client but failed to do so, since my connection timed out.</description></item><item><title>Day 21</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day21/</guid><description>Tried pinging the VM created. Experimented around by creating instances with different subnets, security groups and VPCs linked.
Discovered that security group must have an inbound SSH rule, which has port 22 as ingress.
Finally made a successful SSH connection. Attempted deploying Kubernetes cluster by following this tutorial.
Created a Master Node and established SSH connection.</description></item><item><title>Day 22</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day22/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day22/</guid><description>Attempted deploying Kubernetes cluster by following this tutorial.
Created three VMs to be used as nodes- One Matser, Two Slaves.
Started off by installing packages on the Master Node.
Installed Docker. Referred to official documentation for the same. #Importing some necessary certificates. sudo apt-get install \ &amp;gt; apt-transport-https \ &amp;gt; ca-certificates \ &amp;gt; curl \ &amp;gt; gnupg \ &amp;gt; lsb-release sudo apt install docker.</description></item><item><title>Day 23</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day23/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day23/</guid><description> Spent some time in debugging previous day&amp;rsquo;s error.
Deep-dived into some of the fundamental aspects of cloud computing such as VM, subnets, VPCs and Security Groups.
Started learning about EKS Cluster and its deployment method.
References:
Provisioning an EKS Cluster Creating an EKS Cluster Basics of Cloud Computing</description></item><item><title>Day 24</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day24/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day24/</guid><description>Started working with EKS, following the official Hashicorp documentation
Cloned the following directory.
git clone https://github.com/hashicorp/learn-terraform-provision-eks-cluster Configured AWS in the given directroy.
The directory has various terraform files.
eks-cluster.tf: It provisions all the resources required to setup EKS cluster.
kubernetes-dashboard-admin.rbac.yaml: It creates cluster binding and connects API.
kubernetes.tf: Provisions Kubernetes as a provider along with host and token.</description></item><item><title>Day 25</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day25/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day25/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Day 3</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day3/</guid><description> Integrated CircleCI with my Hugosite repository locally. Though, turned out to be an unsuccessful attempt at the end.
In attempt to launch deploy the website through Github actions, I added gh-pages.yml file to .github/workflows.
Tried sorting out various issues faced during deployment of my site.</description></item><item><title>Day 4</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day4/</guid><description> Added some more content to my website and made changes.
To sort out the issues as mentioned in the previous update, tried changing the remote repository with my Hugo content to &amp;lsquo;.github.io&amp;rsquo;.
After deliberation with my teammates and figuring out the errors, finally managed to host this site successfully. Satwik&amp;rsquo;s PS1 Journey</description></item><item><title>Day 5</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day5/</guid><description> Learnt about Git merge, rebase, and pipelines. Got a gist of some theoritical aspects.
Explored CI/CD in more details, consulted some of my college friends who have some experience in this domain.</description></item><item><title>Day 6</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day6/</guid><description>Tried exploring Docker and Ansible technologies.
Had a healthy group discussion with my friends on the same, where we shared our ideas on both the technologies mentioned above.Many of our misconceptions were cleared up, and we divided responsibilities amongst us.
Installed Docker package and engine on my system. Followed the official Docker documentation and a Youtube Tutorial
Firstly, attempted installing it through the repository method.</description></item><item><title>Day 7</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day7/</guid><description>Created a Hugo group site.
Initialized an empty Hugo site and remotely added it to Github Repository.
Added my group members as collaborators on the repository containing this Hugo Site.
Added an appropriate theme to the site.
Setup the homepage with some relevant content and added a bolg.
Hosted the site locally, even though there were kinks.</description></item><item><title>Day 8</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day8/</guid><description>Installed VS code for my Linux VM.
Downloaded the .deb file from Visual Studio official site.
Installed it by running sudo dpkg -i code_1.57.0-1623259737_amd64.deb on terminal. The VS application can be opened from terminal by using open code ..
Attempted locally hosting the docker image.
Created index.md and about.md files in a repository.
Used command docker run -d -p 8000:80 -v ~/nginxtrial:/usr/share/nginx/md --name trialsite nginx to run it.</description></item><item><title>Day 9</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/day9/</guid><description>Making a Docker container for Hugo site by following a Youtube tutorial.
Made two directories namely ansible-build and docker-build in the Hugo repository. Shifted content of Hugo website to Docker-build.
Made a Dockerfile. Specified Nginx static file location and localhost ports in the file.
Built the Docker container and ran it. Failed in the earlier attempt since I forgot to make Dockerfile.</description></item><item><title>First Week</title><link>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/week0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 06:00:20 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://satwikvats.github.io/posts/daily-updates/week0/</guid><description>It was an amazing week where I got acquainted with a lot of tools which are quintessential for software development industry.
I got to learn the fundamentals of Git, its interface and some basic commands. Experimented around and created a page of my own using Github Pages. My first Github Page Installed a Virtual Machine with Ubuntu on my system for the sake of being able to use Asciinema. Got familiarized with basic terminal commands and Linux configurations.</description></item></channel></rss>